□(+44) 07429 241034 | Signification | Signifi

Summary_

Software Engineer with a 10+ year tech career that includes extensive experience designing and implementing highly available and maintainable software and infrastructure solutions and effective processes for continuous integration, delivery, and deployment. Dynamic skill set includes web development, security, and networking on Unix and Windows systems.

Work Experience

Lead Software Engineer

Pamat

FORM3 IS A CLOUD-NATIVE PAYMENT PROCESSING PLATFORM

Dec. 2019 - Present

- Led a team of 5 developers focused on SEPA payments solutions handling millions of real-time and batch payments monthly. Built using Go, SNS, SQS, Lambda, Docker and PostgreSQL.
- Enhanced distributed systems observability by improving several internal libraries.
- Built an automated code security scanner platform running multiple checks like synk, tfsec, leaking secrets, etc. running thousands of jobs daily. Technologies used Go, Lambda, DynamoDB, Fargate.
- Improved maintainability and testability of multiple Go services, by isolating logic and improving dependency injection.
- Promoted from Senior Engineer to Lead Software Engineer in March 2021.

Senior Platform Engineer - Sky Betting & Gaming

Leed

SKY BETTING & GAMING IS A BRITISH-BASED GAMBLING COMPANY.

Mar. 2016 - Nov. 2019

- Lead developer for an online casino system that mediates interactions (e.g. user account balance checks, updating customer wallets) between
 games providers and internal systems allowing hundreds of game plays per second. Built using Go, Kubernetes, Kafka/Kafka-Connect, and
 MySOL.
- · Developed multiple metrics exporters and improved monitoring infrastructure to help increase systems visibility.
- Built an internal application using Go and Vue.js to redirect traffic and disable gameplay during planned outages by setting or removing attributes from load balancers.
- Wrote common reusable infrastructure configurations to reduce AWS new services deployment time.
- Served as internal SME for Chef and rewrote several cookbooks to modernize coding practices and standards.
- Implemented a scalable Selenium grid that enables hundreds of tests to run every day.
- Analyzed delivery pipelines to identify and resolve pain points. Wrote Groovy (Jenkins) code to orchestrate and parallelize, reducing deployment time and increasing stability.
- Revamped logging processes to improve ability to investigate and resolve issues.
- Advised various development teams to promote the adoption of operations best practices.
- Promoted from Platform Engineer to Senior Platform Engineer in July 2018.

Automation Engineer - Linkedcare

Lisbon

LINKEDCARE WAS A PORTUGUESE STARTUP IN THE E-HEALTH SUBSECTOR.

Nov. 2014 - Mar. 2016

- Implemented and maintained Ansible configuration management spanning several public cloud providers like AWS and DigitalOcean.
- Designed and built a local development environment supported by Docker and CoreOS.
- Implemented Continuous Integration with Shippable and CircleCI and worked with development teams to improve workflows and release processes for new features.

Systems/Application Administrator - Portugal Telecom

Lisbon

PORTUGAL TELECOM IS THE LARGEST TELECOMMUNICATIONS SERVICE PROVIDER IN PORTUGAL.

June 2013 - Nov. 2014

- Deployed and managed provisioning infrastructure for SaaS/laaS services and wrote Powershell automation scripts.
- Developed a python software licensing scanning tool to ensure compliance.
- Provided third-level support for customers and partners in Portugal and Brazil.

Systems/Network Administrator - Refer Telecom

Lisbon

REFER TELECOM IS A RAIL TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND SERVICE PROVIDER.

Oct. 2011 - June 2013

- Developed Cisco automations using Jinja2/Python and implemented version control for all switches and routers configurations.
- Installed and supported CheckPoint, Cisco ASA/FWSM firewalls and Cisco 6590/7K multi-site data center networking equipments.

Prior work includes four combined years as IT Security Administrator and Network/Linux Administrator.

Skills

Go, AWS, Linux, Terraform, Kubernetes, Rancher, OpenTelemetry, OpenCensus, Prometheus, Grafana, Lambda, TFSec, DynamoDB, Packer, Vagrant, Docker, Chef, Ansible, NGINX, Kafka, SQS, SNS, RabbitMQ, Jenkins, CloudFormation, Redis, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Cisco, Checkpoint, Windows Server, Apache, IIS, Bind, Active Directory, HAProxy, Monit, Travis, CircleCI, Shippable, Serverspec, Git, Ruby, Python, Clojure, Bash, Powershell

Education